Shane Murphy

Junior Fullstack Software Developer

Github / Linkedin

Kerry, Ireland / murphyshanedev@gmail.com/ +353 834073425

Summary

I am a Junior Full Stack Software developer and recent graduate of the Code Institute.

Prior to starting my tech journey I mainly worked in the Customer Care industry from which I've gained invaluable experience in team work and communications.

I have always had a keen interest in technology, I love learning and understanding new concepts, I am always motivated to gain new skills and always take pride in my work, whatever it may be.

Education

June 2023 - April 2024 Code Institute Dublin, Ireland (Remote)

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development (Accredited by the University West of Scotland)

Technical Skill Set

Technologies	Databases	Frameworks	Version Control
HTML CSS Javascript Python	MongoDB MySQL ElephantSQL	Django jQuery Bootstrap	Git Github

Portfolio Projects

<u>Cove Creations</u> - Cove Creations is a website designed for selling mode made crafts and paintings. Technologies used to build: HTML. CSS, Python, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Django

<u>Wyldlife Blog</u> - Wildlyfe is a blog application I have created to share, discuss, and engage with others. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, Python, JavaScript, BootStrap

<u>SNOWFALL</u>- SnowFall is in essence, a text based game about surviving the brutal cold of a Tundra. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, Python

<u>Animal Quizdom</u>-. Animal Quizdom is a general knowledge quiz that revolves around wildlife/nature. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

<u>Kingdom Cats</u> - Kingdom Cats is a website for adopting and fostering cats and kittens that need a home. Technologies used to build: HTML, CSS

Collaborative Projects

<u>Hackathon</u> - This is the main marketing website for the Nexus Software development team. It is designed to be responsive and accessible on a range of devices, making it easy to navigate for potential customers. It will include a landing, portfolio and contact page. Our goal is to create an interactive website for a software dev company.

Work Experience

Jul 2022 - Feb 2023 RelateCare Patien

Patient Care Agent

Remote

My role as a Patient Care Agent had many aspects to it from simple appointment scheduling, account creation, insurance, linking in with doctors offices, getting patients to the right departments. I had to learn many unfamiliar systems such as the American system of health insurance and usages of their databases while always adhering to The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA)

Jan 2022 - June 2022 Infosys

Customer Service Specialist

Remote

As a Customer Service Specialist my duties revolved around supporting customers with any questions, queries or concerns they had. Additionally I created accounts for new customers, took payments, and also was able to receive commission for additional products or services taken.

Additional Information/Interests

- I am currently working on building my portfolio website.
- Working on additional certifications
- Regular engagement on Slack tech forum.
- I attend Coding Community meetups online.
- Fluent English, basic Irish

References available on request.